A Guide to the Papers of Julian Bond, 1897-2006
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Series IV: Invitations, Political Associates, and American Program Bureau Papers
  - American Program Bureau- Correspondence, 1977 (Box-folder 64:3)
  - American Program Bureau- Itineraries and Finances, 1968-1972 (Box-folder 64:4)
  - American Program Bureau- Itineraries and Finances, 1973 (Box-folder 64:5)
  - American Program Bureau- Itineraries and Finances, 1974 (Box-folder 64:6)
  - American Program Bureau- Itineraries and Finances, 1975 (Box-folder 64:7)
  - American Program Bureau- Itineraries and Finances, 1981-1982, n.d. (Box-folder 65:1)
  - Invitations- Accepted, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 65:2)
  - Invitations- Accepted, 1969, 1 of 2 folders. (Box-folder 65:3)
  - Invitations- Accepted, 1969, 2 of 2 folders. (Box-folder 65:4)
  - Invitations- Accepted, 1970 (Box-folder 65:5)
  - Invitations- Accepted, 1971 (Box-folder 65:6)
  - Invitations- Accepted, 1972 (Box-folder 65:7)
  - Invitations- Accepted, 1974 (Box-folder 65:8)
  - Invitations- Accepted, 1975 (Box-folder 65:9)
  - Invitations- Accepted, 1976 (Box-folder 65:10)
  - Invitations- Announcements, 1967-1969 (Box-folder 66:1)
  - Invitations- Declined, 1969 May (Box-folder 66:2)
  - Invitations- Declined, 1969 July (Box-folder 66:3)
  - Invitations- Declined, 1969 August, 1 of 2 folders. (Box-folder 66:4)
  - Invitations- Declined, 1969 August, 2 of 2 folders. (Box-folder 66:5)
  - Invitations- Declined, 1969 September (Box-folder 66:6)
  - Invitations- Declined, 1969 October, 1 of 2 folders. (Box-folder 66:7)
  - Invitations- Declined, 1969 October, 2 of 2 folders. (Box-folder 66:8)
  - Invitations- Declined, 1969 November (Box-folder 66:9)
  - Invitations- Declined, 1969 December (Box-folder 66:10)
  - Invitations- Declined, 1970 January (Box-folder 67:1)
  - Invitations- Declined, 1970 February, 1 of 2 folders. (Box-folder 67:2)
  - Invitations- Declined, 1970 February, 2 of 2 folders. (Box-folder 67:3)
  - Invitations- Declined, 1970 March (Box-folder 67:4)
  - Invitations- Declined, 1970 April-May (Box-folder 67:5)
  - Invitations- Declined, 1970 June-August (Box-folder 67:6)
  - Invitations - Declined, 1970 August-November (Box-folder 67:7)
  - Invitations- Declined, 1970 December (Box-folder 67:8)
  - Invitations- Declined, 1971 January-February (Box-folder 68:1)
  - Invitations- Declined, 1971 March-April (Box-folder 68:2)
  - Invitations- Declined, 1971 May-July (Box-folder 68:3)
  - Invitations- Declined, 1971 August-October (Box-folder 68:4)
  - Invitations- Declined, 1971 November (Box-folder 68:5)
  - Invitations- Declined, 1971 December (Box-folder 68:6)
  - Invitations- Declined, 1972 January-February (Box-folder 68:7)
  - Invitations- Declined, 1972 March (Box-folder 68:8)
  - Invitations- Declined, 1972 April-May (Box-folder 69:1)
  - Invitations- Declined, 1972 June-August (Box-folder 69:2)
  - Invitations- Declined, 1972 September (Box-folder 69:3)
  - Invitations- Declined, 1972 October (Box-folder 69:4)
  - Invitations-Declined, 1972 November-December (Box-folder 69:5)
  - Invitations- Declined, 1973 January-February (Box-folder 69:6)
  - Invitations- Declined, 1973 March-May (Box-folder 69:7)
  - Invitations- Declined, 1973 June-October (Box-folder 69:8)
  - Invitations- Declined, 1973 November-December (Box-folder 70:1)
  - Invitations- Declined, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 70:2)
  - Invitations- Declined, 1976 January-July (Box-folder 70:3)
  - Invitations- Declined, 1976 August-October (Box-folder 70:4)
  - Invitations- Declined, 1976 November-December (Box-folder 70:5)
  - Invitations- Declined, 1977 January-May (Box-folder 70:6)
  - Invitations- Declined, 1977 June-August (Box-folder 70:7)
  - Invitations- Declined, 1977 September (Box-folder 70:8)
  - Invitations- Deferred, 1971 January-May (Box-folder 70:9)
  - Invitations- Deferred, 1971 June (Box-folder 70:10)
  - Invitations- Deferred, 1972 (Box-folder 71:1)
  - Invitations - Deferred, 1973 January-July (Box-folder 71:2)
  - Invitations- Deferred, 1973 August-December (Box-folder 71:3)
  - Invitations- Deferred, 1974 (Box-folder 71:4)
  - Invitations- Not Answered, 1967-1969 (Box-folder 71:5)
  - Invitations- Not Answered, 1974-1977 (Box-folder 71:6)
  - Invitations- Not Answered, 1987, n.d. (Box-folder 71:7)
  - Political Associates- Contracts, 1972 (Box-folder 71:8)
  - Political Associates- Contracts, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 71:9)
  - Political Associates- Contracts, 1977 (Box-folder 71:10)
  - Political Associates- Correspondence, 1971-1981 (Box-folder 71:11)
  - Political Associates- Finances, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 71:12)
  - Political Associates- Finances, 1973 January-February (Box-folder 71:13)
  - Political Associates- Finances, 1973 March-May (Box-folder 71:14)
  - Political Associates- Finances, 1973 June-September (Box-folder 72:1)
  - Political Associates- Finances, 1973 October-December (Box-folder 72:2)
  - Political Associates- Finances, 1974 (Box-folder 72:3)
  - Political Associates- Finances, 1975-1977 (Box-folder 72:4)
  - Political Associates- Itineraries, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 72:5)
  - Political Associates- Mailing List, 1972-1974, n.d. (Box-folder 72:6)
  - Political Associates- Proposal Toward a Black Political Party- A Study, 1971 October (Box-folder 72:7)
- Series V: Academic Papers, Speeches, and Writings chiefly by Authors Other Than Bond
  - Article- Is George Wallace Now a Racial Moderate? by Morris Dees, [post 1972] (Box-folder 73:1)
  - Article-State of the Art Historians and the Civil Rights Movement by Adam Fairclough, 1990 (Box-folder 73:2)
  - Article- Freedom's Warriors The Fighting Black Clergy An Historical Overview by Jerry M. Guess from The Crisis, 1990 (Box-folder 73:3)
  - Article- Lichtenstein's Fictions Revisited: Race and the New Labor History in New Politics by Herbert Hill, 1999 (Box-folder 73:4)
  - Article- Martin Luther King's Constitution: A Legal History of the Montgomery Bus Boycott by Randall Kennedy, 1989 April (Box-folder 73:5)
  - Article- Patterns of Black Politics by Martin Kilson, 1995 (Box-folder 73:6)
  - Article- Freedom Then, Freedom Now: The Historiography of the Civil Rights Movement by Steven F. Lawson, 1991 April (Box-folder 73:7)
  - Article- 25 Years Later: A Sanitized Sixties by Edward P. Morgan, [1993?] (Box-folder 73:8)
  - Article- No Diplomatic Immunity: African Diplomats, the State Department, and Civil Rights, 1961-1964 by Renee Romano, [2000] (Box-folder 73:9)
  - Proposed Article concerning Julian Bond by Peter E. Steward, including copies of early correspondence with Bond (1957-1963), 1969-1970 (Box-folder 73:10)
  - Articles concerning the South in Graphic by George C. Stoney, 1940-1941 (Box-folder 73:11)
  - Article- Southern Negro: 1952 Warning to Ike and the Dixiecrats, 1952 September 27 (Box-folder 73:12)
  - Bibliography- Negro Progress in Atlanta, Georgia 1961-1970 compiled by Annie L. McPheeters, 1972 (Box-folder 73:13)
  - Book  Changing Patterns in the New South (Southern Regional Council), [1955] (Box-folder 73:14)
  - Book-Religion, Race, and Justice in a Changing America by Gary Orfield and Holly Lebowitz Rossi, editors, 1999, 1 of 2 folders. (Box-folder 73:15)
  - Book  Religion, Race, and Justice in a Changing America by Gary Orfield and Holly Lebowitz Rossi, editors, 1999, 2 of 2 folders. (Box-folder 73:16)
  - Chapters from Miscellaneous Published Books, ca. 1969-1986, n.d. (Box-folder 73:17)
  - Class Packet- Race and Class: The Modern Movement for Civil Right (AFAMS 400F) Julian Bond, n.d. (Box-folder 73:18)
  - [Class Packet ?]- Historical Tripos- Martin Luther King, Jr. and the Civil Rights Movement, 1993 (Box-folder 73:19)
  - Class Packet- Maryland State Archives: Documents for the Class Room From Segregation to Integration: The Donald Murray Case, ca. 1991 (Box-folder 73:20)
  - Class Packet- History of the Civil Rights Movements (AFRO AM 236) by Michael Thelwell, 1995 Fall (Box-folder 74:1)
  - Dissertation- Racial Discrimination and Minority Business Enterprise: Evidence from the 1990 Census by Jan Scott Wainwright, 1997 August (Box-folder 74:2)
  - Interview with Horace Julian Bond by John Britton, Howard University and correspondence about it, 1991-1992, 1968 January 22, 2 copies. (Box-folder 74:3-4)
  - Interview with Julian Bond by William Chafe, 1990 December 18 (Box-folder 74:5)
  - Interview- A Conversation with Julian Bond edited by Trevor L. Chandler, Seattle, Washington, 1974 November 7 (Box-folder 74:6)
  - Interview with Horace Julian Bond by Marsha Darling, 1995 February 6 (Box-folder 74:7)
  - Interview with Julian Bond by Jeffrey M. Elliot, 1983 (Box-folder 74:8)
  - Interview with Julian Bond by Elizabeth Gritter at Bond's American University office, 1999 November 1, 22 (Box-folder 74:9)
  - Interview with Julian Bond by Megan Lisagor in Hoo Knows, 1998 May (Box-folder 74:10)
  - Interview with Julian Bond, Straight Talk by Ulysses Prince, III, 1984 February (Box-folder 74:11)
  - Interview with Julian Bond by Plater Robinson, 1997 June 4 (Box-folder 74:12)
  - Interview with Julian Bond by Thomas Rose and John Greenya in Black Leaders: Then and Now, 1984 (Box-folder 74:13)
  - Interview with Julian Bond, Georgia State Senator, by Mr. Scavullo, n.d. (Box-folder 74:14)
  - Interview with Julian Bond in Southern Exposure published by the Institute for Southern Studies, 1976 (Box-folder 74:15)
  - Interview with John Robert Lewis by Archie Allen, 1969 February 14 (Box-folder 74:16)
  - Interviews concerning John Robert Lewis by Archie Allen, 1968-1969, 1 of 2 folders. (Box-folder 75:1)
  - Interviews concerning John Robert Lewis by Archie, 1968-1969, 2 of 2 folders. (Box-folder 75:2)
  - Interview with Erline McQueen by Margaret Fuller and Dr. Jim Pitts, Ties That Bind Project, 2003 (Box-folder 75:3)
  - Manuscript concerning Aaron Henry The Fire Ever Burning by Constance Curry, 1997 June (Box-folder 75:4)
  - Paper- Unite or Perish: The Contours of Black Radical and Nationalist Thought, 1954-1975 by Ernest Allen, Jr. and John H. Bracey, Jr., 1991 April (Box-folder 75:5)
  - Paper- [The Roles of Women in Civil Rights Struggles] by Sally Belfrage, 1989 May 31-June 2 (Box-folder 75:6)
  - Paper- The Politics of the Outsider: The Black Man's Role in American Politics by Lerone Bennett, Jr., 1967 September (Box-folder 75:7)
  - Paper-Night Comes to Berea College: The Day Law and the African-American Reaction by Scott Blakeman, 1996 January (Box-folder 75:8)
  - Paper- The Negro in the Armed Forces of the United States Prior to World War I by Horace Mann Bond, 1943 (Box-folder 75:9)
  - Paper- Women in the Civil Rights Movement by Anne Braden, 1988 November 30 (Box-folder 75:10)
  - Paper-"Trends in Feminism and Historiography Invisible Revolutionaries: White Women in Civil Rights Historiography" by Joan C. Browning, 1996 (Box-folder 75:11)
  - Paper- Women's Consciousness and the Nonviolent Movement Against Segregation 1960-1965 A Personal History by Sandra Cason, 1989 (Box-folder 75:12)
  - Paper- Cold War Culture and the African-American Struggle for Freedom by William H. Chafe, n.d. (Box-folder 75:13)
  - Paper- The Negro Elected Official in the Changing American Scene by Dr. Kenneth [Bancroft ?] Clark, 1967 September (Box-folder 75:14)
  - Paper- Politics and Race in the American System by Martin Kilson and Clement Cottingham, 1992 September (Box-folder 75:15)
  - Paper- We Want to be Part of This Democratic Society in Which We Live: Legal Abstractions, Local Realities, and the Claiborne County (Mississippi) Civil Rights Movement by Emilye Crosby, 1997 April (Box-folder 75:16)
  - Paper- They Don't Understand What It Takes in Mississippi: The National NAACP and the Claiborne County (Mississippi) Civil Rights Movement by Emilye Crosby, 1997 March (Box-folder 75:17)
  - Paper- 'They Will Not Fight in the Open' African Americans Strategies of Resistance in the Early Twentieth Century by Greta de Jong, 1997 December (Box-folder 75:18)
  - Paper- The Black Image in the White Mind Media and Race in America by Robert M. Entman and Andrew Rojecki, n.d. (Box-folder 75:19)
  - Paper- Documenting the Costs of Slavery, Segregation, and Contemporary Discrimination: Are Reparations in Order for African-Americans? by Joe R. Feagin for the Washington University Conference, 2001 February 8 (Box-folder 75:20)
  - Paper- The Representative Party Platform by William K. Floyd, n.d. (Box-folder 75:21)
  - Paper- Blacks and the Constitution: The Civil War and Reconstruction by Eric Foner, n.d. (Box-folder 75:22)
  - Paper- Where Martin Luther King, Jr., Was Going: 'Where Do We Go From Here' and the Traumas of the Post-Selma Movement, by David J. Garrow, 1991 (Box-folder 75:23)
  - Paper- Black North Carolina, the NAACP, and the Origins of the Civil Rights Movement;: 1945-1955 by Raymond Gavins, n.d. (Box-folder 75:24)
  - Paper- Black Female Reformers in the Age of Segregation: The Emergence of Civil Rights in the Old North State by Raymond Gavins, n.d. (Box-folder 75:25)
  - Paper- America is the Black Man's Battlefield: Anti-war Activities on Historically Black Colleges and Universities, 1965-1972 by Gerald Gill, n.d. (Box-folder 76:1)
  - Paper- American Management Association's Choice Paternalism or Economic Inclusion for Black Americans by Raymond Griswold and James A. Marshall, 1969 May (Box-folder 76:2)
  - Paper- New York Times v. Sullivan and Its Times [by?] Kermit Hall, University of Tulsa, Oklahoma, 1993 March (Box-folder 76:3)
  - Paper- The Struggle for Racial Equality in the Formation of the United Nations by Robert L. Harris, Jr., n.d. (Box-folder 76:4)
  - Paper- Ethnic Education: Its Purposes and Prospects by James A. Hirabayashi, n.d. (Box-folder 76:5)
  - Paper- Coalition and Conflict: Martin Luther King, Civil Rights, and the American Labor Movement by Michael Honey, 1992 October (Box-folder 76:6)
  - Paper- Race and Suffrage in the South Since 1940 by Luther P. Jackson, 1948 June (Box-folder 76:7)
  - Paper- From Moderation to Engagement: White Liberal Intellectuals and Civil Rights, 1954-1959 by Walter A. Jackson, 1992 November (Box-folder 76:8)
  - Paper- Congested Terrain: Race, Space, and Resistance on Birmingham Public Transportation During World War II by Robin D.G. Kelley, 1992 (Box-folder 76:9)
  - Paper- We Are Not What We Seem: Rethinking Black Working Class Opposition in the Jim Crow South by Robin D.G. Kelley, n.d. (Box-folder 76:10)
  - Paper- Women and Civil Rights- A Personal Recollection by Mary E. King, 1995 October 5 (Box-folder 76:11)
  - Paper- Two Small Windows of Opportunity: Black Politics in Georgia During the 1940s, and the Pertinent Oral History Sources Today by Clifford M. Kuhn, 1992 February 29 (Box-folder 76:12)
  - Paper-Prophets of Protest: Black Women Leaders in the Civil Rights Movement by Joyce Ladner, 1989 May 31-JunE 2 (Box-folder 76:13)
  - Paper- Miscegenation in Southeast Georgia: A Pioneer Family in Baker, Decatur, and Dougherty Counties by James H. McCleary, 1996 April (Box-folder 76:14)
  - Paper- The Impact of South Carolina Negroes in Politics by John H. McCray, 1982 November (Box-folder 76:15)
  - Paper- The World Conference Against Racism: Through A Wider Lens, by Gay McDougall, 2002 (Box-folder 76:16)
  - Paper- Highlights of Freedom Movements in the South by Marge Manderson, 1981 July (Box-folder 76:17)
  - Paper- Race, Sex, and Rock & Roll: The Chuck Berry Mann Act Trials of 1959-1961, by John Edwin Mason, 1993 (Box-folder 76:18)
  - Paper- Attorneys Black and White: A Case Study of Race Relations Within the NAACP by August Meier and Elliott Rudwick, n.d. (Box-folder 76:19)
  - Paper- Abbey Lincoln's 'Straight Ahead': Jazz in the Era of the Civil Rights Movement by Ingrid Monson, 1996 March (Box-folder 76:20)
  - Paper- Reading Race into the Scopes Trial: African-American Elites, Science, and Fundamentalism by Jeffrey P. Moran, 2003 December (Box-folder 76:21)
  - Paper- ESCRU: The Episcopal Society for Cultural and Racial Unity 1959-1967 by John Morris, 1995 June (Box-folder 76:22)
  - Paper- Down to Now: Memory, Narrative, and Women's Leadership in the Civil Rights Movement by Kathryn L. Nasstrom, 1997 February (Box-folder 76:23)
  - Paper- From Politics to School to Politics" The Minority Student Cycle by William E. Nelson, Jr., 1974 November (Box-folder 76:24)
  - Paper- "Race and Testing in College Admissions" by Michael T. Nettles, Laura W. Perna, and Catherine M. Millet, 1998 February (Box-folder 76:25)
  - Paper- Brightly Shining Lights: SNCC and the Woman Question by Martha Norman, 1989 November 10 (Box-folder 77:1)
  - Paper- Reading About the Movement by Martha P. Norman, n.d. (Box-folder 77:2)
  - Paper- Not Turning Around, Not Turning Back: The Legacy and Challenge of Sixties Activism by Martha Norman, n.d. (Box-folder 77:3)
  - Paper- Activists, Soldiers, and Warriors: Finding and Placing Ourselves in History by Martha Norman, n.d. (Box-folder 77:4)
  - Paper- One Thing We Did Right: Protest, History, and the Civil Rights Movement by Robert Novell, n.d. (Box-folder 77:5)
  - Paper- The FBI and the NAACP by Kenneth O'Reilly, 1990 (Box-folder 77:6)
  - Paper- Westley W. Law and the Convergence of the Civil Rights and Historic Preservation Movements in Savannah, Georgia, 1945-1984 by Albert Oetgen, 1999 (Box-folder 77:7)
  - Paper- Campus Re-segregation and its Alternatives by Gary Orfield, n.d. (Box-folder 77:8)
  - Paper- The Globalizing Economy and Prospects for Improved U.S.-African Economic Relations by Ronald D. Palmer, 1998 (Box-folder 77:9)
  - Paper- Men Lead, But Women Organized: Movement Participation of Women in the Mississippi Delta by Charles Payne, 1988 (Box-folder 77:10)
  - Paper- The Black Urban Regime: Structural Origins and Constraints by Adolph Reed, Jr., n.d. (Box-folder 77:11)
  - Paper- Minority Economic Development-Where To? by Howard J. Samuels, n.d. (Box-folder 77:12)
  - Paper- The Rise of the NAACP in Virginia during the 1930s- A Look at Richmond by Larissa M. Smith, 1998 (Box-folder 77:13)
  - Paper- Administration of Multi-Ethnic Programs by Norvel Smith, 1974 November (Box-folder 77:14)
  - Paper- Central Avenue Breakdown by Al Cecil Taylor and Stephen Propes, 1998 (Box-folder 77:15)
  - Paper- A Public Affairs Concern for Justice and Decency for Black Servicemen and Black Vietnam Veterans by Wallace Terry, [1975] (Box-folder 77:16)
  - Paper- Operation Freedom and the Mississippi Movement by Jerry Thornbery, 1996 March (Box-folder 77:17)
  - Paper-Municipal Politics and the Course of the Civil Rights Movement by J. Mills Thornton, III, 1988 May (Box-folder 77:18)
  - Paper- I Went to Law School to Fight Segregation: Oliver W. Hill versus Jim Crow in Virginia by Peter Wallenstein, n.d. (Box-folder 77:19)
  - Paper- And After Chicago by Arthur I. Waskow, n.d. (Box-folder 77:20)
  - Paper- The Religious Upwelling on the Left by Arthur I. Waskow, n.d. (Box-folder 77:21)
  - Paper- Flirting with Success: The Minority College Graduate and the American Labor Market by Dr. John W. Waters, n.d. (Box-folder 77:22)
  - Paper- The Negro Vote in the South by Palmer Weber, 1938 November (Box-folder 77:23)
  - Paper- Black Electoral Participation: A Paradigm and Application by Carolyn Sue Williams, n.d. (Box-folder 77:24)
  - Paper- Captain Hollowell: Atlanta Negro Politics and the Pye-Webb-Hollowell Campaign of 1964, n.d. (Box-folder 78:1)
  - Paper- Turning Right Judicial Selection and the Politics of Power, Leadership Conference on Civil Rights Education Fund, 2004 July (Box-folder 78:2)
  - Paper- I Can No Longer Bear What I Have Borne: Resistance to Slavery in Late Eighteenth Century Virginia, n.d. (Box-folder 78:3)
  - Paper- Issues of Race, Gender, and Class in the Southern Conference Movement, n.d. (Box-folder 78:4)
  - Paper- Wednesdays in Mississippi: The National Council of Negro Women and the Civil Rights Movement in Mississippi during Freedom Summer, 1964, n.d. (Box-folder 78:5)
  - Poems, n.d. (Box-folder 78:6)
  - Poems- Six Poems on War and Peace by Langston Hughes, reprinted from Gandhi Marg., inscribed For Julian- Langston, 1967 February, Autograph for Vault. (Box-folder 78:7)
  - Report- A Study of Factors Involved in the Identification and Encouragement of Unusual Academic Talent Among Underprivileged Populations by Horace Mann Bond, 1967 January (Box-folder 78:8)
  - Report- The Civil Rights Telecommunications Forum: Building a Movement-Based Structure for Expanding Democracy and Civil Rights in a Digital Age by The Civil Rights Project, 1996 (Box-folder 78:9)
  - Report- Brown at 50: King's Dream or Plessy's Nightmare? by Gary Orfield and Chungmei Lee, 2004 January (Box-folder 78:10)
  - Report- The Long Shadow of Jim Crow Voter Intimidation and Suppression in America Today by People for the American Way Foundation and the NAACP, ca. 2004 (Box-folder 78:11)
  - Report- Modest Progress: The Narrowing Spatial Mismatch Between Blacks and Jobs in the 1990s by Steven Raphael and Michael A. Stoll, 2002 December (Box-folder 78:12)
  - Report- Affirmative Action Review Report to the President, 1995 (Box-folder 78:13)
  - Review- The Tragedy of Scholarship: David Levering Lewis's 'W.E.B. Du Bois', n.d. (Box-folder 78:14)
  - Speeches by Others- A through G, 1967-1998 (Box-folder 78:15)
    Including: Anne Broder, Shirley Chisholm, Kenneth B. Clark, Leroy D. Clark, William Jefferson Clinton, Frederick Douglass (from the Web), David G. Du Bois, John W. Gardner, Paul M. Gaston, and Julian Goodman.
  - Speeches by Others- J through W, 1941-2000 (Box-folder 78:16)
    Including: Jesse Jackson, Lyndon Baines Johnson, John Lewis, Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr., Justice Thurgood Marshall, Thabo Mbeki, James G. O'Hara, Franklin D. Roosevelt, William L. Taylor, Judge J. Harvie Wilkinson, III.
  - Student Papers, 1966-1973 (Box-folder 79:1)
  - Student Papers concerning Julian Bond, 1966-1969 (Box-folder 79:2)
  - Student Papers concerning Julian Bond, 1971-1973, 1977, n.d. (Box-folder 79:3)
  - Teaching Guide 'Eyes on the Prize' Events of the Civil Rights Movement by Plater Robinson, [1985?] (Box-folder 79:4)
  - Thesis- Birth of Consciousness: Activism at Spelman College, 1953-1965 by Molly Blank, 1998 April (Box-folder 79:5)
  - Thesis- Home Sweet Home: the African-American Housing Crisis in Chicago, 1940-1950 by Cornelius Lyn Bynum, 1996 January (Box-folder 79:6)
  - Thesis- The Role of the Young Women's Christian Association in Shaping the Gender Consciousness of the Student Non-Violent Coordinating Committee, 1960-1965 by Abigail Sara Lewis, 1999 (Box-folder 79:7)
  - Thesis- The Impact of Democratic Delegate Selections Rules Changes on Post-Reform Presidential Politics by John Patrick Sullivan, 1991 May (Box-folder 79:8)
  - Thesis- In Pursuit of a Changing Dream: Spelman College Students and the Civil Rights Movement, 1955-1962 by Karen Elizabeth Vanlandingham, 1985 (Box-folder 80:1)
  - Thesis- A Preliminary Report on the Status of the Negro in Dallas County, Alabama by Harris Wofford, 1953 January (Box-folder 80:2)
- Series VI: Political Papers
  - Subseries A: General
    - Address Cards, n.d. (Box-folder 80:3)
    - Address Lists, 1960, 1967-1969 (Box-folder 80:4)
    - Address Lists, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 80:5)
    - Address Lists, 1973-1977 (Box-folder 80:6)
    - Address Lists, n.d. (Box-folder 80:7)
    - Address Lists, n.d. (Box-folder 80:8)
    - Address Lists- Atlanta Legal Aid Society, Inc., 1976 (Box-folder 80:9)
    - Address Lists- Black Ministers, 2004 (Box-folder 80:10)
    - Address Lists- Potential Bond Campaign Supporters, n.d. (Box-folder 81:1)
    - Address Lists- Press, 1966-1976 (Box-folder 81:2)
    - Address Lists- Press, n.d. (Box-folder 81:3)
    - Ashby Street Station Area Development Plan, 1973 April (Box-folder 81:4)
    - Atlanta Elections, 1969-1971 (Box-folder 81:5)
    - Atlanta Elections, 1972-1973, n.d. (Box-folder 81:6)